Andrés Arboleda

Software Developer



- Barcelona
- □ andarbech1@gmail.com
- +34613555895
- in Andres Arboleda Echavarria
- Andarbech
- * andarbech

Hard Skills

- Azure Data Factory
- Azure Synapse
- Azure Purview
- Micosoft Fabric
- Azure Functions
- Azure Web Apps
- -----
- Power Automate
- PowerApps
- SQL Server
- PowerBl
- React
- Javascript /Typescript
- Python
- PySpark
- .Net core / C#

Languages

English Spanish

Soft Skills

Effective communication

Time management

Critical thinking

Problem solving

Professionalism

Teamwork

Curiosity

Continuous learning

Summary

I am a dyamic and experienced technology consultant with record of accomplishment in delivering complex projects and bespoke solutions. My core expertise lies in configuration of Microsoft products, more specifically Dynamics 365, Power Platform, Azure Data Solutions, Azure Web Apps and Azure Data Factory. My knowledge of coding languages enables me to take these low-code platforms to the next level and achieve outstanding results for my clients. I strive not to limit myself to the strictly technical knowledge. That is why I put a strong emphasis on developing soft skills and gaining understanding of business operations. I believe that to deliver exceptional outcomes technical consultants like me need to be good communicators and team players with impecable work ethic and time management skills.

Professional Experience

Digital Transformation Consultant | Microsoft Developer

AlsviorGlobal &

March 2022 - September 2023 | Barcelona, Spain

As a Digital Transformation Consultant at Alsvior Global I worked on a number of high profile engagements where I was able to put my skills at use and further gain advanced knowledge of a wide range of cloud based tools, including Azure Data Factory, Azure Purview, Azure Synapse, and SQL Server. This expertise allows me to confidently create tools and processes that enable efficient data management at all stages - from data capture through storage and transformation, to BI and analytics.

On several projects I was able to help our team respond to complex requirements and business needs by enriching low-code solutions with programming languages such as Python, C#, Typescript and Javascript.

One of the standout projects I have undertaken is the Renewable Energy Company initiative. In this project, I utilized Canvas Apps to create custom components, including the PowerApps component framework (PCF), within the canvas app. These components are designed to address the distinct operational requirements of different departments, promoting efficiency.

Furthermore, I led the establishment of a comprehensive data architecture within the Azure environment. By integrating various Azure services such as Azure Data Factory, Synapse, Databricks, Azure Functions, Data governance, and SQL Server, I provided departments with up-to-date and unified data. This architecture facilitates streamlined operations and generates insightful reports to support informed decision-making processes.

Additionally, I leveraged PowerBI to optimize dashboard performance. Through the creation of queries, views, and stored procedures, I ensured that data remains consistently updated and interconnected across different departments, thereby enhancing the overall efficiency of our data-driven processes.

Full Stack Developer

Assembler Institute of Technology

June 2021 - February 2022 | Barcelona, Spain

1.200 hours of work in a a real work environment. More than 30 Full Stack development projects using MongoDB. ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS (MERN Stack) and Linux, Apache, Mysql, PHP (LAMP Stack). Technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, Redux, Yarn, Docker or Jest among others applying Scrum Agile Methodology, Git and Clean Code practises OOP, MVC and testing.

Education

MSc in Software Developemnt

Assembler Institute of Technology

June 2021 – February 2022 | Barcelona, spain

BSc in Business Administration

Seville University

September 2015 - January 2021 | Seville, Spain

- Valuation of Investment Projects.
- Financial risk management.
- Company financial planning and asset management financial.

Awards

Entrepreneur

Participant Explorer SanBank Program Bilbao 2019

For 12 weeks, received training and transformed the project Farm Assistant into a versatile and actionable solution.

Ideas Factory 2021 - 1st Award

University Pablo de Olavide, de Sevilla

1st May 2021

Found profitable and actionable solutions in the field of sustainable agriculture

Hobbys & Interests

Chess | Salsa Dancing

Magic Realism Books